Guide to the Family Life Development Center records, 1974-2010.
Family Life Development Center records, 1974-2010
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Family Life Development Center records, 1974-2010.
23-13-2854
New York State College of Human Ecology.Family Life Development Center.
21.9 Cubic Feet.
Manuals, videotapes, DVDs, CDs, booklets, manuscripts, dolls
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Historical information, guides and manuals, booklets, teaching material, curricula, and drafts of a text on family life; includes five anatomical dolls formerly used in child abuse cases, and articles representing opposing opinions on the use of dolls and material from the Child Protective Services Training Institute. Also, videtapes of Professor James Garbarino appearing on television discussing youth and guns.
Also seven DVDs and one leaflet relating to the conference: The Immigrant Child: Past, Present and Future which was put on by the Family Life Development Center in the College of Human Ecology in October of 2008. Joan Jacobs Brumberg was the project director.
Also 13 DVDs of various presentations, including the Iscol Family Program for Leadership Development in Public Service.
Includes records and 10 CDs concerning the Family Life Development Center Military Projects.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; Garbarino, James.; Child Protective Services Institute.; Iscol Family Program for Leadership Development in Public Service.
Subjects:
Family life education--New York State--Ithaca.; Child abuse--Study and teaching
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Additional material and digital versions can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/8130
SERIES LIST
Series I. Articles and Papers Concerning FLDC
Boxes: Box 2, folders 1, 5; Box 3, folder 1
Series II. Curriculum
Subseries A: Handbooks and Manuals
Boxes: Box 1, folders 1-2, 5-6, 8, 26-27; Box 2, folder 2
Subseries B: Child Protective Services Training Institute (1971-2003)
Boxes: Box 2, folder 6; Boxes 6-22
Series III. Reports/Proposals/Subject Files
Boxes: Box 1, folders 4, 7; Box 2, folders 7-8; Box 3, folders 2-3
Series IV. Reviews
Boxes: Box 1, folders 9-24; Box 3, folders 4-6
Series V. National Data Archive on Child Abuse and Neglect
Box 25
Series VI. The Military Projects
Box 26, Box 27
Subseries A: Army Family Advocacy Program
Box 26
Subseries B: Various Advocacy Programs
Box 27
Series VII. Dolls Used in Counseling Sessions
Boxes: 4-5
Series VIII. Conferences and Presentations
Box: 23
Subseries A: Iscol Family Program for Leadership Development in Public Service
Subseries B: John Doris Lectures
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Articles and Papers Concerning FLDC
  - Articles concerning child abuse from FLDC staff (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - John Doris' Articles and Papers (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, memos, flyers, about the Family Life Development Center, 1974-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - I Can Make a Difference - Brochures, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cornell Youth and Work Program Brochures, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series II: Curriculum
  - A. Handbooks and Manuals
    - Parents and School Partnerships for Preventing Child Abuse: Handbook for Schools and Communities (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Coordinating Services for Abused Adolescents: Star Project Manual (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Escape: Preventing C/A in the Harvest, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - One Company-One Kid: A Guide, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - What's a Teacher To Do?: Booklet, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Interviewing/Treating the Incestuous Family" (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Suspected Child Abuse and Maltreatment, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Community Handbook on Child Abuse and Neglect-FLDC, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Summer Series, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - B. Child Protective Services Training, Institute (1973-2001)
    - New York State Child Protective Service Training Institute (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Danish, Steven J. and Allen L. Hauer. Helping Skills: A Basic Training Program. Trainee's workbook and leader's manual., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Foundation for Educational Services. Child Abuse and Neglect Handbook for Medical Professionals, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Gouge, Jerry. The Case Mangement Model: Concept, Implementation and Training. Regional Institute of Social Welfare Research, Inc. Volume III., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - ---. The Case Management Model: Implementation Requirements. Regional Institute of Social Welfare Research, Inc. Volume III., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - ---. The Case Management Model: Trainers Guide Regional Institute of Social Welfare Research, Inc. Volume III., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hawk, William. Focus: Child Abuse and Neglect Interventions for Health Care Providers Trainee Manual., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - ---. Trainer manual. Segments I-VI, appendices., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - ---. Focus: Child Abuse and Neglect Interventions for Physicians. Trainee manual., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - ---. Trainer manual. Segments I-IV, appendices, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Hilson, ARthur. A Guide to Planning in Child Protective Services in New York State., 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Katzive, Marion C. A Caseworker's Guide to the New York State Juvenile Justice System., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Kinney, T., et al. Child Care Training: Needs Assessment School of Social Welfare, SUNY ALbany, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Reprint 1980
    - ---. Child Welfare: Case Recording Curriculum. Modules I-III., 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - ---. Modules IV-V. Appendices I-V., 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Lift a Finger: The Administrator's Role in Combating Child Abuse and Neglect. A manual for use by school administrators on reporting child abuse and neglect, 1974-07-1975-06 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Lift a Finger: The Citizen's Role in Combating Child Abuse. Guide for use with large group instruction, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Lift a Finger: The Teacher's Role in Combating Child Abuse, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Lift a Finger: The Young Adult's Role in Preventing Child Abuse and Neglect, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - National Center for Comprehensive Emergency Services to Children. Comprehensive Emergency Services: Community Guide 2nd ed., 1974 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - ---. Comprehensive Emergency Services: Training Guide. 2nd ed., 1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - O'Reilly, C., and S. Sherman. Training Program in Child Abuse and Neglect. School of Social Welfare, SUNY Albany. Sections 1-7., 1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - ---. Appendix A, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - ---. Appendix B., 1975 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Overberger, Carla, et al. Problem-Solving in EPSDT. Trainee workbook, training guide B., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Schimke, Karen, et al. Goal-Oriented Social Work Services: a Workbook, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Sundel, M. Local Child Welfare Services Self-Assessment Manual. Parts I-III., 1978-01 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - ---. Parts IV-VI, 1978-01 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Parts VII-VIII, 1978-01 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Understanding Child Maltreatment: Help and Hope. A course ot study (pilot edition)., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Caldwell, Marie C., and Angelo Conorozzo Child Protection Services. Training for DSS in the Westerin New York Region. Module I., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - ---. Module II., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - ---. Module III., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - ---.Child Protection Services Investigation Planning (Northern Counties) Training. Training for Department of Social Services in the western New York region., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - ---.Child Protection Services Investigation Planning (Southern Counties) Training. Training for DSS in the western New York Region. Module I., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Child Protective Service Instructional Development Project: Community Resources. Washington State Dept. of Social and Health Services/School of Social Work, University of Washington., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Child Protective Services, Northern Training. SUNY Buffalo. Modules I, II, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - ---. Module III and Investigation Planning (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - ---. Investigation Planning and Team Leader Training: Supervision (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Child Protective Services Task Analysis. Booklet, slides, cassette tape., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Child Protective Services Training, Lake Placid, NY (3 parts), 1979-06-25-1979-06-29 (Box 7, Folder 11-13)
    - CPSTI.Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Services Workers.(3 parts) With A Community Handbook on Child Abuse and Neglect., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
    - CPSTI. NYS Child Protective Services training agenda, days 1 and 2., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - ---. Days 3 and 4., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - ---. Days 5, 6 and 7., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - ---. Days 8, 9 and 10. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Golden, Janet, et al. Undergraduate Child Welfare Curriculum Development Project. Course syllabi. Syracuse University School of Social Work., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Green, J. Stages of Invervention: An Outline for Protective Services Workers. Handbook, slides, cassette tape., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - New York State Police Academy.Instructor Development Course: Child Abuse and Neglect., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Protective Services: Decision-Making Training Curriculum. New Jersey curriculum., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Specialized Training for Child Protective Services Workers: A Curriculum on Child Abuse and Neglect., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Stuyvesant, R. What to do About Child Abuse: A Manual for Training Child Care Providers. Day Care Crisis Council., 1979 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Urzi, Mary.Cooperative Approaches to Child Protection. Minnesota Department of Public Welfare., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Alvy, Kerby, et al.Black Parent Training Programs. Center for the Improvement of Child Caring, Studio City, CA., 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bolton, F.G., et al. CPS Basic Training. Voume II. Module III, Section B. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - ---. Module III, sections C, D. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - ---. Module IV, sections A, B. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - ---. Module IV, section C. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - ---. Module IV, sections D, E. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Child Welfare: Notes for Practice, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - CPSTI. Assessment in Child Protective Services., 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - CPSTI. Basic Training for Child Protective Services Workers. (2 parts), 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
    - CPSTI. A Curriculum on Therapeutic Techniques in Crisis Control for the Child Care Worker (2 parts), 1981 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
    - ---. Participant Manual (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - ---. Trainee's Manual (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - ---. Trainee's Manual (draft) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - CPSTI. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Services Workers Module I., 1982 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - ---. Module II. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - ---. Module III (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - ---. Module IV. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - CPSTI. Legal Aspects of Residential Child Care Work. Part 3 of 3., 1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - CPSTI. Orientation to Child Protective Service Work in New York State. (5 part), 1980 (Box 8, Folder 21-25)
    - CPSTI. Therapeutic Physical Restraing in Crisis Control for the Child Care Worker. Trainee's Manual. Part 2 of 3., 1982 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - CPSTI.Therapeutic Techniques in Crisis Control for the Child Care Worker. Participant manual., 1982 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - CPSTI. Training for New York Cty Child Protective Services Supervisors., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - A Curriculum Guide for Child Protection, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - A Curriculum Guide for Family Violence: Its Relationship to Child Abuse and Maltreatment (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - ---. Appendix. (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Griffin, William and Patrick Tooman. Advanced Investigation Training for Child Protective Services., 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - ---. Trainer's Manual (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Lero, Donna S. and Susan de Rijcke-Lollis.Child Abuse: An Instructor's Manual and Resource Guide., 1980 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Steppe, Stephanie. The Legal System. Child Protective Services Instructional Development Project. Cassette tapes, slides. (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Vinokur, Diane and Geraldine Jackson. Attitudes and Evaluation of In-Service Training by Local Administrators. National Child Welfare Training Center., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Assessment in Child Protective Services. Advanced training for NYS Child Protective Service workers., 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Bandas, Judith, et al. High Risk Factors for Children Under Six., 1983-1984; 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Budlong, Michael and Andrea Mooney. Therapeutic Crisis Intervention for the Child Care Worker. Instructor's guidebook, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - ---. Instructor's guidebook (draft.) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - ---. Instructor's manual, sections I, II. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - ---. Instructor's Manual, section III. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - ---. Instructor's manual, sections IV, V, VI, and appendix. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - ---. Instructor's manual, training resources, child care resources. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - ---. Therapeutic Crisis Intervention for the Child Care Worker.. (2nd edition--3 parts), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
    - CPSTI. Assessment in Child Protective Services. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Service Workers., 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - CPSTI. Cultural Issues in Child Protective Services., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
    - CPSTI. Cultural Sensitivity in Child Protective Services., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - CPSTI. Investigation of Out-of-Home Child Abuse and Neglect. Training maual., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - CPSTI. Medical Issues in Child Protective Services., 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - CPSTI. Specialized Training in the Investigation of Out-of-Home Child Abuse and Neglect Cases. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Services staff. (2 parts)., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
    - CPSTI. Trainer's Pages for Advanced Legal Desk Reference Manual., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Elementary CPS Skills Training Handbook. (2 parts), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 20-21)
    - Galster-Ryan, Constance, et al. Medical Issues in Child Protective Services. Trainer's Manual., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - ---. Specialized Training in the Investigation of Out-of-Home Child Abuse and Neglect Cases. Guidebook for Montana Child Protective Services Staff., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - --. Appendices (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - ---. Specialized Training in the Investigation of Out-of-Home Child Abuse and Neglect Cases. Guidebook for Georgia Child Protective Services staff., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - ---. Days 1 to 3. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - ---. Appendices. (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Griffin, William. Legal Desk Reference Manual. CPSTI., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Griffim, William and Patrick Tooman. Advanced Investigation Training for Child Protective Services. Participant's manual., 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Polowy, Michael, et al. New York State Child Welfare Reform Act and Permanency Planning Core Curriculum. Trainer's manual. (3 parts.), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 30-32)
    - Bandas, Judith, et al. Administering CPS. Participant's guidebook. CPSTI., 1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - ---. Trainer's manual. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - ---. Module I; "Pre-Investigation/Investigation. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - ---. Module II: "Legal Issues." (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Module III: "Dynamics and Assessment" (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - ---. Module IV: "Case Management" (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - ---. Cultural Issues in Child Protective Services. Participant's manual. CPSTI. (3 parts), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
    - ---. Guidebook for New York State Child Protective Service Staff. Volume I, Modules I and II. CPSTI., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - ---. Volume II, Modules II and IV. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - ---. Investigation and Assessment of Child Abuse and Neglect. Guidebook for the Virgin Islands Child Protective Services Staff. CPSTI. (2 parts)., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
    - ---. Sexual Abuse Trainer's Manual. CPSTI., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Bolton, F.G., et al. CPS Basic Training Modules. Special Populations and Projects Unit. Volume I, Module I, sections A, B, C, D. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - ---. Volume I, Module II, sections A, B, C, D. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - ---. Volume I, Module III, section A. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Cherry, Florence J. High-Risk Parenting. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Services Staff., 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - ---. Appendices. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - ---. The High Risk Parenting Trainer's Manual. CPSTI., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - ---. The High Risk Parenting Trainer's Manual. (2 parts), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 21-22)
    - ---. Participant's Manual for High Risk Parenting. CPSTI., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - CPSTI. Sexual Abuse., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - ESCAPE, New York State Education Department. Preventing Child Abuse in the Harvest: A Handbook for Migrant Educatiors. (2 parts), 1984 (Box 10, Folder 25-26)
    - Griffin, William and Patrick Tooman. Advanced Ivestigation Training for Child Protective Services. CPSTI., 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - ---. Investigation Issues in Child Protective Services. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Service Staff. CPSTI., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Griffin, et al. On-Call Guidebook CPSTI., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Griffin, William. Workbook for the Legal Desk Reference Manual. CPSTI., 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - New York State Department of Social Services. The High Risk Parent. 1984. (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Perez, Norma and Joyce Morris. Training Curriculum for Host Home Program Volunteers. Guide for Host Home Program Coordinators., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Rivera, Julia and Patrick Tooman. Cultural Issues in Child Protective Services. Trainer's manual. CPSTI. (2 parts), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 33-34)
    - Tooman, Patrick. Core Training for Supervisors. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Service Staff. CPSTI. Volume I., 1984 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - ---. Volume II. (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Arjona, Leila, et al. Peronal Safety Programs to Prevent Sexual Abuse of Pre-School Children: A User's Guide to Day Care Centers in New York City. (draft), 1986 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - ---. Appendices. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - ---. A Pre-School Personal Safety Curriculum to Prevent Sexual Abuse for Day Care Centers in New York City., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Child Care 310: Supervised Practicum I. School of Child Care, University of Virginia., 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 4-14)
    - CPSTI. Confidential Investigation Unit 3-Day Training Program., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - ---. Investigation of Child Abuse and Maltreatment in Residential Care., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - ---. Investigation in Out-of-Home Care (IOHC) Conference. (5 parts)., 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 17-21)
    - ---. Medical Issues in Child Protective Services., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Fritsche, Nancy, et al. Specialized Training in the Investigation of Out-of-Home Child Abuse and Neglect. National Residential Child Care Training Project., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - ---. Days one, two, and three (p2-47). (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - ---. Appendix I. (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - ---. Appendix II. (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - ---. Appendix III. (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - ---. Appendix IV. (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - ---. Bibliography and appendices. (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Griffin, William and Patrick Tooman. Investigation Issues for Child Protective Services. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Service Staff. CPSTI., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Harrigan, C. Frank, et al. Supplement to Legal Desk Reference. CPSTI., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Jaklitsch, Barbara Weiss. STAR Buddy Training System: Adolescent Abuse. Workbook Manual. Statewide Teamwork for Abused Runaways., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - ---. Resource manual. (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - McCabe, Mary Ann. Sexual Abuse. CPSTI., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Mooney, ANdrea, et al. Therapeutic Crisis Intervention. Instructor's manual. CPSTI., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Schecter, Susan. Domestic Violence: Battered Women. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Service Staff., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Tooman, Patrick. Core Training for Supervisors. New York State Child Protective Service Staff. Volume II., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Wegenest, David, et al. Basic Training for Social Services Staff: a Resource Book. New York State Child Welfare Training Institute., 1986 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Abramczyk, Lois, et al. Treatment Training for Child Welfare Workers. Center for Child and Family Studies, University of South Carolina. (3 parts)., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - Barry, Frank. Coordinating Services for Abused Adolescents: How to Do It. Statewide Teamwork for Abused Runaways (STAR)., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Clark, Preston A. Restraing and Isolation Review for IAB Investigators. Instructor's manual. CPSTI., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - ---. Participant's manual (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - CPSTI. Children at Risk., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - ---. Guidebook for the NYS Child Protective Services Staff. Volume I: The Report, The Investigation., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - ---. Week One: The Report, The Investigation (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - ---. Volume I: Training Exercises (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - ---. Volume II: The Service Plan, the Courts. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - ---. Volume II: Training Exercises. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - ---. Investigation in Out-of-Home Care. Guidebook, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - ---. Medical Issues in Child Protective Services., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - ---. Medical Issues in Child Protective Services (expanded) (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - ESCAPE Project Performance Report. Final Report. (2 parts), 1987 (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
    - Fritsche, Nancy. Advanced Investigative Interviewing--IOHC. Guidebook. CPSTI., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Fritsche, Nancy and Patrick Tooman. CPS Isues for Non-CPS Staff. CPSTI., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Jaklitsch, Barbara Weiss. STAR Buddy Training System: Adolescent Abuse Workbook Manual. Statewide Teamwork for Abused Runaways., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Mooney, Andrea, et al. Thereapeutic Crisis Intervention. Instructor's manual. The National Residential Child Care Project., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Mooney, Andrea. Domestic Violence. Guidebook for NYS Child Protective Service Staff., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Tooman, Patrick. Sexual Abuse: The Use of Anatomical Dolls With Children., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - ---. Sexual Abuse Issues. NYS Child Protective Service Staff., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - CPSTI. Children at Risk. Ed. Marney Thomas, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - ---. Draft Trainer's Manual for Core Training. Week One: The Report, the Investigation. p. 1-55., 1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - ---. Week one, p. 56-130. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - ---. Week one, p. 131-139, and Module III (CA/M) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Module III, days 6-10 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - ---. Draft trainer's manual, cannibalized version. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - ---.Therapeutic Crisis Intervention. Student guidebook. (2 parts)., 1989 (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
    - Fritsche, Nancy, et al. Adolescent Maltreatment Guidebook., 1989 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Fritsche, Nancy. IAB Management Seminar Series. Part II: Assertive Supervision and Negotiation Skills., 1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - ---. Part III: Conflict Negotiation and Motivation (Box 13, Folder 11)